Pinelands Folklife Project collection
American Folklife Center, Library of Congress
- Series 3: Field documentation arranged by fieldworker, Field photography descriptions are copied directly from B and C logs via Optical Character Recognition, so errors and abbreviations exist.
  - Joseph P. Czarnecki
    - Field photography on black-and-white film
      - Trapping with Tom Brown, Millville, New Jersey, November 17, 1983, AFC 1991/023: 217992-22; Joseph P. Czarnecki; PFP-83-BJC-217992-22; 37 black-and-white film negatives (35mm)
        Trapping with Tom Brown. G-Millville; no code]. All photos are bad due to pressure plate problem. See PFP-83-CJC-073-083 logs for picture information.
      - Trapping with Tom Brown, Millville, New Jersey, November 17, 1983, AFC 1991/023: 217992-26; Joseph P. Czarnecki; PFP-83-BJC-217992-26; 37 black-and-white film negatives (35mm)
        Trapping with Tom Brown G-Millville; no code] A few(?) usable photos, mostly bad due to pressure plate problem. See PFP-83-CJC-073-083 logs for picture information.
      - Oystering out of Port Norris, New Jersey, November 14, 1983, AFC 1991/023: 217992-29; Joseph P. Czarnecki; PFP-83-BJC-217992-29; 38 black-and-white film negatives (35mm)
        Oystering out of Port Norris. See Jens Lund's notes for details. All frames bad due to pressure plate problem; 1-4, Tools and captain; 5-36, Crew sorting oysters.
      - Oystering out of Port Norris, New Jersey, November 14, 1983, AFC 1991/023: 217992-30; Joseph P. Czarnecki; PFP-83-BJC-217992-30; 36 black-and-white film negatives (35mm)
        Oystering out of Port Norris. See Jens Lund's notes for details; 2-12, Crew members sorting out crabs, fish, shells, etc.; 13-22, The chute that drops oysters into the "cages"; 23-27, The dredge; 28-29, 33-37, Crew members; 30-32, Oysters going up the conveyor belt from the dredge.
      - Trapping with Tom Brown, Millville, New Jersey, November 17, 1983, AFC 1991/023: 217992-31; Joseph P. Czarnecki; PFP-83-BJC-217992-31; 37 black-and-white film negatives (35mm)
        Trapping with Tom Brown G-Millville; no code] Virtually all photos are bad due to pressure plate problem. See PFP-83-CJC-073-083 logs for picture information.
      - Trapping with Tom Brown, Millville, New Jersey, November 15, 1983 to November 17, 1983, AFC 1991/023: 217992-34; Joseph P. Czarnecki; PFP-83-BJC-217992-34; 37 black-and-white film negatives (35mm)
        Trapping with Tom Brown G-Millville; no code] All frames except #25 are bad due to pressure plate problem. See PFP-83-CJC-073-083 logs for picture information.
      - Oystering out of Port Norris, New Jersey, November 14, 1983, AFC 1991/023: 217992-36; Joseph P. Czarnecki; PFP-83-BJC-217992-36; 36 black-and-white film negatives (35mm)
        Oystering out of Port Norris. See Jens Lund's notes for details; 1-4, Joseph Czarnecki (shot by Jens Lund); 5-9, Jens Lund; 10-15, One of the crew members; 16-22, Oysters; 23-24, The dredge; 25-26, The crew sorting oysters; 27-32, The sorting apparatus as seen from the bow of the boat looking toward the wheelhouse; 33-36, Views from the boat coming into port.
      - Interiors, Mrs. Hitchner's house, Possum Trot, New Jersey, November 13, 1983, AFC 1991/023: 217993-01; Joseph P. Czarnecki; PFP-83-BJC-217993-01; 6 black-and-white film negatives (35mm)
        Interiors of the upstairs of Mrs. Hitchner's house. Bedroom. See Mary Hufford's notes for details. Mrs. Hitchner is Brad Thompson's aunt. G-Possum Trot; 27GT.
      - Interiors of Mrs. Hitchner's house, Possum Trot, New Jersey, November 13, 1983, AFC 1991/023: 217993-02; Joseph P. Czarnecki; PFP-83-BJC-217993-02; 12 black-and-white film negatives (35mm)
        Interiors of Mrs. Hitchner's house at G-Possum Trot; 27GT. See Mary Hufford's notes and tapes for details; 1-5, Detail, upstairs bedroom; 6-12, Old staircase, living room to upstairs.
      - Marsh with drainage ditch; Tom Brown, Millville, New Jersey, 1984, AFC 1991/023: 221130-01; Joseph P. Czarnecki; PFP-84-BJC-221130-01; 34 black-and-white film negatives (35mm)
        3-8, Marsh with drainage ditch; 9-14, Tom Brown leaning on stick; 15-22, Tom Brown walking away from camera into the tall grasses; 24-28, Tom Brown standing in road in woods; 29-36, Tom Brown in truck.
      - Tom Brown, Millville, New Jersey, 1984, AFC 1991/023: 221130-02; Joseph P. Czarnecki; PFP-84-BJC-221130-02; 37 black-and-white film negatives (35mm)
        1-20, Torn Brown moving through tall grass carrying cloth bag; 22-27, Tom Brown standing in road holding animals by the tall and sack in other hand; 28, Grasses; 29-31, Pelts on wall; 32-35, Closeup of furs; 36, Folded pelts.
      - Tom Brown, Millville, New Jersey, 1984, AFC 1991/023: 221130-03; Joseph P. Czarnecki; PFP-84-BJC-221130-03; 37 black-and-white film negatives (35mm)
        All frames: Tom Brown out hunting.
      - Exterior and Interior shots of Tom Brown Trapper building, New Jersey, 1984, AFC 1991/023: 221130-04; Joseph P. Czarnecki; PFP-84-BJC-221130-04; 34 black-and-white film negatives (35mm)
        All Frames: Exterior and Interior shots of TOM BROWN TRAPPER building.
      - Tom Brown out checking traps, Millville, New Jersey, 1984, AFC 1991/023: 221130-05; Joseph P. Czarnecki; PFP-84-BJC-221130-05; 37 black-and-white film negatives (35mm)
        1-19, Tom Brown out checking traps; 20-27, Tom Brown removing animal from trap; 28-36, Tom Brown continuing to check his traps.
      - Tom Brown, Millville, New Jersey, 1984, AFC 1991/023: 221130-06; Joseph P. Czarnecki; PFP-84-BJC-221130-06; 38 black-and-white film negatives (35mm)
        1-3, Tom Brown in pickup truck; 3-17a, Tom Brown checking traps; 18a-25a, Tom holding animal from trap; 18-36, Tom Brown from the back, bending over to check something.
      - Tom Brown out hunting, Millville, New Jersey, 1984, AFC 1991/023: 221130-07; Joseph P. Czarnecki; PFP-84-BJC-221130-07; 37 black-and-white film negatives (35mm)
      - Visit with Jack Cervetto, Warren Grove, New Jersey, March 1984, AFC 1991/023: 222306-01; Joseph P. Czarnecki; PFP-84-BJC-222306-01; 36 black-and-white film negatives (35mm)
        Visit with Jack Cervetto G-Warren Grove; 56GT; 1-26, Jack in the luncheonette at Warren Grove; 27-36, Jack Cervetto.
      - George Campbell, salt hay farm, Eldora, New Jersey, March 1984, AFC 1991/023: 222306-02; Joseph P. Czarnecki; PFP-84-BJC-222306-02; 35 black-and-white film negatives (35mm)
        George Campbell's salt hay farm G-Eldora; 34GT; 1-4, On the tractor going out to the ditching and banking site; 5-7, George walking near ditching and banking site; 8-35, Ditching and banking site. 12-19, 29-35 have George and his earth-moving equipment in them.
      - Jack Cervetto cutting cedar "beanpoles," Warren Grove, New Jersey, March 1984, AFC 1991/023: 222306-03; Joseph P. Czarnecki; PFP-84-BJC-222306-03; 37 black-and-white film negatives (35mm)
        1-16, Jack Cervetto cutting cedar "beanpoles" G-Warren Grove; 56GT; 17-37, Close-ups of Jack Cervetto.
      - Lou Peterson's boat, Bivalve, New Jersey, March 21, 1984, AFC 1991/023: 222306-04; Joseph P. Czarnecki; PFP-84-BJC-222306-04; 37 black-and-white film negatives (35mm)
        1-4, ??? Something related to Lou Peterson's boat In Bivalve?; Bivalve; 5-37, Corking (caulking) procedure as performed by Larry Baglio. See PFP-84-CJC-016-017 and PFP-84-FJC0321 for details.
      - Darlington's cranberry bogs, Whitesbog, New Jersey, March 1984, AFC 1991/023: 222306-05; Joseph P. Czarnecki; PFP-84-BJC-222306-05; 19 black-and-white film negatives (35mm)
        Darlington's bogs G-Whitesbog; 21GT; 1, Sluice gates? Black stuff may be creosote; Clifford Frazee family photos G-Forked River; 49GT; 2-3, Cliff with deer, ca. 1943; 4-5, Cliff with Model T, ca. 1942; 6-7, Cliff with gun, ca. 1937; 8-19, Out-takes; 21-22, Lucinda and Job Penn, great-grandfather and greatgrandmother (father's mother's parents); 23, Cliff with turtles, ca. 1965; 24-25, Cliff' s grandfather?
      - George Campbell, salt hay farm, Eldora, New Jersey, March 1984, AFC 1991/023: 222306-06; Joseph P. Czarnecki; PFP-84-BJC-222306-06; 37 black-and-white film negatives (35mm)
        George Campbell's salt hay farm G-Eldora; 34GT; 1-3, Ditching and banking site; 4-6, George and his earth-moving equipment; 7-8, Tires used as landfill; 9-14, George; 15-17, Ditching and banking site; 18-20, George Campbell and Gene Hunn; 21-37, George Campbell except for 26 (unidentified pile of something).
      - Larry Baglio and the corking operation; Lou Peterson working on his boat at the Bivalve packing plant, Bivalve, New Jersey, March 21, 1984, AFC 1991/023: 222306-07; Joseph P. Czarnecki; PFP-84-BJC-222306-07; 37 black-and-white film negatives (35mm)
        1-25, Larry Baglio and the corking (caulking) operation.SeePFP-83-CJC-016-017 and PFP-83-FJCO321 for details in Bivalve; 26-37, Lou Peterson working on his boat at the Bivalve packing plant. He is using a cutting (acetylene) torch and also an arc welder, and is in the process of replacing an old rope steering mechanism with a device of his own making that uses chains.
      - Sand roads and trails in the pygmy forest, Woodland, New Jersey; Newly designed bog, one of Darlington's, Whitesbog, New Jersey, March 1984, AFC 1991/023: 222306-08; Joseph P. Czarnecki; PFP-84-BJC-222306-08; 31 black-and-white film negatives (35mm)
        1-8, Sand roads and trails in the pygmy forest (plains) G-Woodland; 27GT; 9, Newly designed bog, one of Darlington's G-Whitesbog; 21GT; 10-11, "Florence" (ruins), near Whitesbog; 12-13, "Rome" (ruins); 14-16, Dam; 16-19, New bogs as in 9; 20, Sluice gate; 21-23, One of many pumphouses which move water in and out of the bogs; 24-30, Bogs as in 9; 31, Cranberry plants in the bogs.
      - Jack Cervetto, Warren Grove, New Jersey; Sugar sand and sand road in the pygmy forest (plains), Woodland, New Jersey, March 1984, AFC 1991/023: 222306-09; Joseph P. Czarnecki; PFP-84-BJC-222306-09; 37 black-and-white film negatives (35mm)
        1-10, Close-ups of Jack Cervetto G-Warren Grove; 56GT; 11-13, Jack and his truck; 14-17, Jack cutting cedar "beanpoles"; 18-27, Jack (except for stand of cedar where he had been cutting in 22); 26-27, Jack and Gene Hunn; 30, Jack; Sugar sand and sand road in the pygmy forest (plains) G-Woodland; 27GT.
      - George Campbell's salt hay farm; Lou Peterson working on his boat at Bivalve; Larry Baglio corking (caulking) a boat in Bivalve, New Jersey, March 21, 1984, AFC 1991/023: 222306-10; Joseph P. Czarnecki; PFP-84-BJC-222306-10; 36 black-and-white film negatives (35mm)
        Visit with George Campbell's salt hay farm G-Eldora; 34GT; 1-10, On the tractor going out to the ditching and banking site; 11-12, George, Gene Hunn, machine; 13-17, George and his machine; 18-19, Load of tires to be used for fill; 20-23, Salt hay bales; 24, Sign for Campbells' crabbing and fishing pay pond; 25-29, Lou Peterson working on his boat at Bivalve; 30-36, Larry Baglio corking (caulking) a boat in Bivalve. See PFP-84-CJC-016-017 and PFP-84-FJC0321 for details.
      - Clifford Frazee family photographs, Forked River, New Jersey, March 1984, AFC 1991/023: 222306-11; Joseph P. Czarnecki; PFP-84-BJC-222306-11; 2 black-and-white film negatives (35mm)
        Clifford Frazee family photos G-Forked River; 49GT; 1A-2A, Cliff's grandfather (?)
      - Tom Brown processing hide, Millville, New Jersey, March 1984, AFC 1991/023: 223764-01; Joseph P. Czarnecki; PFP-84-BJC-223764-01; 30 black-and-white film negatives (35mm)
        1-6, Tom Brown skinning possum; 7-20, Fleshing possum on fleshing machine; 21-30, Possum hide on stretcher.
    - Field photography on color slide film
      - C log (color photo log), Joseph P. Czarnecki; 129 manuscript pages (8.5 x 14 inch or smaller) (Box-folder 13/115)
      - Landmark Baptist Church, Browns Mills, New Jersey, October 2, 1983 to October 3, 1983, AFC 1991/023: CJC-001; Joseph P. Czarnecki; PFP-83-CJC-001; 23 color film transparencies (35mm slide)
        Landmark Baptist Church G-Browns Mills; 21GT Sunday service, October 2; 1, Elaine Thatcher setting up recording equipment; 2, Placard at front of church; 3, Rev. John Becker taking communion; 4, Deacon H. A. Miller handing out communion wine; 5, Wall map at back of church showing missionary locations; 6, Communion table in front of congregation; 7, Congregation singing; 8, Deacon Miller speaking; 9, Beginning of communion service; 10, Congregation member singing solo, 11, Rev. Becker taking communion evening; 12, Congregation member giving testimony; 13, Deacon Miller receiving communion wine for distribution; 14, Deacon Miller distributing communion wine; 15, Deacon Miller taking communion wine, G-Waretown; 53GT; 16-17, Methodist Church; 18, Bingo advertisement in front of G-Waretown; 53GT Fire Dept.; 19, POW/MIA Bill board on G-Rte. 72: GT
      - Yam harvest, Middltown, New Jersey; Pygmy forest; Just before sunrise on a misty morning, October 4, 1983, AFC 1991/023: CJC-002; Joseph P. Czarnecki; PFP-83-CJC-002; 24 color film transparencies (35mm slide)
        Yam harvest G-Middletown; 36GT; 1, Boxes for collecting harvested yams; 2-11, Harvesting yams. Farmer's name is Leonard Maglicoccio; Pygmy forest, also called Dwarf Forest and G-The Plains; 27GT; 12-14, Pictures made from a hard-packed sand/gravel road which goes into the forest from near the Gulf station on Rte. 72; 15-16, Location, same as above, sunset; 20, Same as 15-16; 17-18, Just before sunrise on a misty morning at G-Makepeace Lake; 26GT from Rte. 563
      - Photos in Woodbine, New Jersey; Haines Bogs, New Jersey; Play horse made out of a log, Cassville, New Jersey, October 4, 1983 to October 5, 1983, AFC 1991/023: CJC-003; Joseph P. Czarnecki; PFP-83-CJC-003; 20 color film transparencies (35mm slide)
        Photos 1-10 in G-Woodbine; 47GT; 1-2, Woodbine Synagogue; 3, Fireplug near St. Casimir's Church; 4-7, 70-year old house across the street from St. Casimir's Church; 8-9, Old woman sitting in front of a barber shop, main street of Woodbine; 10, Roadside stand, outside Woodbine; Haines Bogs G-Chatsworth; 27GT; 11-16, Sunset over a dead cedar swamp near Haines' cranberry bogs; 17-18, Play horse made out of a log, south of G-Cassville; 48GT
      - Cranberry harvest at Haines' cranberry bogs, Chatsworth, New Jersey, October 5, 1983, AFC 1991/023: CJC-004; Joseph P. Czarnecki; PFP-83-CJC-004; 24 color film transparencies (35mm slide)
        Cranberry harvest at Haines' cranberry bogs south of G-Chatsworth; 27GT; 1-3, Bill Haines, Jr. opening sluice gates to control the flow of the water from one bog to another; 4-20, Puerto Rican workers harvesting cranberries by pushing "beaters" through the bogs. A leader sets the pace and leads the workers through the areas to be harvested
      - Cranberry harvesting at Haines' cranberry bogs, Chatsworth, New Jersey, October 5, 1983, AFC 1991/023: CJC-005; Joseph P. Czarnecki; PFP-83-CJC-005; 37 color film transparencies (35mm slide)
        Cranberry harvesting at Haines' Cranberry Bogs G-Chatsworth; 27GT; 1-8, "Hogging" cranberries, i.e., bringing the floating cranberries together so they can be scooped up and loaded. Boards are used to skim the water surface; 9-12, Cranberries are loaded onto a truck using a conveyor belt set into the water; 13, Bill Haines Jr. examining a cranberry plant; 14-16, Pushing cranberries onto the conveyor belt for loading; 17, Good cranberries are sorted from the bad in the processing plant by allowing them to drop and bounce. The good ones bounce down onto the conveyor belt while the bad ones fall back; 18, Sorted cranberries being loaded for shipping; 19, Bill Haines checking the berries; 20, Overall view of the bogs
      - Bill Haines Jr.'s cranberry harvest; Erosion at an abandoned sand mine near the old New Jersey Central Railroad; Pine trees in the pygmy forest at sunset (off Route72), October 5, 1983, AFC 1991/023: CJC-006; Joseph P. Czarnecki; PFP-83-CJC-006; 22 color film transparencies (35mm slide)
        Bill Haines' Jr. cranberry harvest G-Chatsworth; 27GT; 1, Haines checking cranberries before shipping; 2-4, Cranberries ready for shipping; 5-15, Erosion at an abandoned sand mine near the old New Jersey Central Railroad G-Woodmansie; 27GT; 16-20, Pine trees in the pygmy forest at sunset (off Rte. 72) G-Woodland; 27GT
      - Joe Reid, Waretown, New Jersey, October 6, 1983, AFC 1991/023: CJC-007; Joseph P. Czarnecki; PFP-83-CJC-007; 25 color film transparencies (35mm slide)
        1-8, Joe Reid of G-Waretown; 53GT building one of his garveys; 9, Cedar boat lumber drying in the yard; 10, Joe Reid and his son; 11-16, Joe Reid
      - Garveys built by Joe Reid; The Ahearns preparing to go out crabbing, Waretown, New Jersey, October 6, 1983, AFC 1991/023: CJC-008; Joseph P. Czarnecki; PFP-83-CJC-008; 19 color film transparencies (35mm slide)
        1-8, Garveys built by Joe Reid, harbors at G-Waretown; 53GT; 9-14, The Ahearns preparing to go out crabbing
      - Roadside stands, New Egypt, New Jersey; Father Konstantin of the Russian Church, Cassville, New Jersey, October 6, 1983, AFC 1991/023: CJC-009; Joseph P. Czarnecki; PFP-83-CJC-009; 25 color film transparencies (35mm slide)
        1-8, Roadside stand in G-New Egypt; 54GT; 9, Rita Moonsammy buying vegetables; 10-12, Father Konstantin of the Russian Church in G-Cassvilie; 48GT; 13-18, Various Russian icons, handicrafts, utensils, etc. on display in the small museum of the Russian church; 19, Steeple of the Russian Church
      - Medford Apple Festival, Medford, New Jersey, October 8, 1983, AFC 1991/023: CJC-010; Joseph P. Czarnecki; PFP-83-CJC-010; 23 color film transparencies (35mm slide)
        Medford Apple Festival G-Kirby's Mill; 18GT; 1, Selling apples; 2-4, Bake-off; 5, Square dancers; 6, Selling cider; 7, Making apple butter; 8, Old-fashioned blacksmith; 9, and 12 Dollmakers; 10, Children; 11, Quiltmaker; 13, Woodworker; 14-16, Square dancers; 17-18, Overall view; 19, Dried plant seller; 20, Basket seller
      - Medford Apple Festival, Medford, New Jersey, October 8, 1983, AFC 1991/023: CJC-011; Joseph P. Czarnecki; PFP-83-CJC-011; 21 color film transparencies (35mm slide)
        Medford Apple Festival G-Kirby's Mill 18GT; 1, Needlecrafts; 2, Decoy seller; 3, Doll sellers; 4, Selling cider; 5, Squeezing fresh cider using an old press; 6, Broomseller's stand; Mac Hoeh's Crab-In G-Tuckerton; 47GT; 7, Butch Hoeh; 8, Sue Samuelson interviewing Mr. Hoeh; 9, Hoeh and wife; 10, Mrs. Hoeh; 11-14, Crab-in participants; 15, Hoeh and his business partner; 17, Opening clams; 18, Checking out the crab catch
      - Hamilton Township Day Festival, New Jersey, October 8, 1983, AFC 1991/023: CJC-012; Joseph P. Czarnecki; PFP-83-CJC-012; 19 color film transparencies (35mm slide)
        Hamilton Township Day Festival G-Mays Landing; 1OGT; 1, Cheerleaders; 2, Making funnel cakes; 3, Boy scouts; 4, Scouting patches; 5, Merit badges; 6-12 and 16, Miscellaneous scenes at the festival; 13-15, Cheerleaders
      - Tom Brown, trapper, Millville, New Jersey, October 10, 1983, AFC 1991/023: CJC-013; Joseph P. Czarnecki; PFP-83-CJC-013; 24 color film transparencies (35mm slide)
        Tom Brown, Trapper G-Millville; GT; 1, Mailbox; 2, Baskets of traps; 3-11, Tom Brown; 12, Birdhouses; 13-14, Entrance to Tom Brown's trapper's cabin; 15, Hand painted decorative skin stretchers; 16, Torn Brown with a noose device of his own making which he uses to immobilize animals caught in traps; 17, An old water heater modified into a vat used for dipping and coating traps; 18-20, Tom Brown in front of the entrance to his trapper's cabin
      - Tom Brown, trapper, Millville, New Jersey, October 10, 1983, AFC 1991/023: CJC-014; Joseph P. Czarnecki; PFP-83-CJC-014; 25 color film transparencies (35mm slide)
        Tom Brown, Trapper G-Millville; GT; 1, "Japanese" style garden pool; 2, Pumpkins; 3, Poem by Tom Brown; 4, Torn Brown in his garden; 5-6, Torn Brown's garden; 7, Chimney built by Torn Brown; 8, Tom Brown; 9-14, Interiors, room adjoining kitchen; 15-17, Tom Brown's living room
      - Auto junk sculptor William Clark near Buena, New Jersey, October 10, 1983, AFC 1991/023: CJC-015; Joseph P. Czarnecki; PFP-83-CJC-015; 29 color film transparencies (35mm slide)
        Auto junk sculptor William Clark, six miles north of G-Buena; 03GT; 1-14, William Clark and his auto junk sculpture
      - Interview with Bill Wasiowich, Woodmansie, New Jersey, October 6, 1983 to October 11, 1983, AFC 1991/023: CJC-016; Joseph P. Czarnecki; PFP-83-CJC-016; 31 color film transparencies (35mm slide)
        Initial meeting with Bill Wasiowich (William Wasiowich according to his spelling as painted on the side of his truck) at his home in G-Woodmansie; 27GT with Eugene Hunn; 01, Cat-tails gathered by Bill for sale to a plant dealer in Whiting; 02, Washtub pall and strap used for collecting pine cones; 03, Bill Wasiowich; 04, Bill standing in front of a large shed he built from railroad ties salvaged from the old New Jersey Central Railroad, which runs about 50 yards from his house; 05, Construction detail of Bill's shed; 06-09, Same as 4; 10, Bill in front of his house; the railroad bed is atop the grassy knoll in the right side of the frame; 11-12, Sphagnum moss collected by Bill drying on the ground; 13, Bill with a device he made to compress and bale sphagnum moss; 14-16, Bill and his railroad tie shed. (plant), (technology), gathering; Bill Wasiowich harvesting pine cones in G-Woodmansie; 27GT; 17, Vegetation near the pygmy forest where Bill harvests pine cones; 18-19, Bill and his truck, with pine cone gathering tub in 19 gathering, (plant)
      - Gathering pine cones and moss, Woodmansie, New Jersey, October 11, 1983, AFC 1991/023: CJC-017; Joseph P. Czarnecki; PFP-83-CJC-017; 23 color film transparencies (35mm slide)
        Bill Wasiowich harvesting pine cones and sphagnum moss G-Woodmansie; 27GT; 01-05, Bill Wasiowich harvesting pine cones in the pygmy forest. (plant), gathering; Bill Wasiowich harvesting sphagnum moss, near G-Brookville; 53GT; 06-13, Harvesting the moss. The boards serve as a road through the swamp for the wheelbarrow. (plant). gathering
      - Clifford Frazee at his cedar cutting grounds near Brookville, New Jersey, October 7, 1983, AFC 1991/023: CJC-018; Joseph P. Czarnecki; PFP-83-CJC-018; 26 color film transparencies (35mm slide)
        At the cedar cutting grounds of Clifford Frazee, near G-Brookville; 53GT; 01, Live cedars growing in the swamp; 02-04, Clifford Frazee digging up old charcoal pits in the pine forests near his cutting area. These pits could be as much as 200 years old; 05-08, Cut down cedar forest with live cedars yet to be harvested in the background. In 06 and 07 boughs of cedar cover a corduroy road. They will settle in after being run over by a truck several times, forming a spongy but quite serviceable road; 09, A large cut cedar, perhaps about 75 years old; 10, Frazee's corduroy road. Bark trimmed off the cedars in the sawmill operation, along with thinner cedars too small to be used for lumber, form the base of the road while cedar boughs are piled on top to fill in the spaces; 11-20, Clifford Frazee standing on his corduroy road-in-progress, with the yet-to-be-harvested cedar forest in the background. (plant ), trees
      - Clifford Frazee at his cedar cutting grounds near Brookville, New Jersey, October 7, 1983, AFC 1991/023: CJC-019; Joseph P. Czarnecki; PFP-83-CJC-019; 24 color film transparencies (35mm slide)